Guide to the William Cannicott Olson Papers, 1956-1985
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
William Cannicott Olson papers 1956-1985
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Olson, William Cannicott.
7.8 Linear Feet 7877 Items
Graduate of Duke University and chair of the History Department at Marist College in Poughkeepsie, N.Y.
Collection contains mainly papers pertaining to his work in the field of education. Prior to his position at Marist College, he taught history in Danville, Va. He was active in the Danville Education Assoc., and became the Virginia Education Association's president. In addition to professional correspondence, there is a great deal of personal correspondence with family and friends much of which relates to his life as a homosexual. Included also are financial papers, printed materials, clippings, addresses, writings (including a draft of his dissertation), and other records. There is some memorabilia from Olson's school days. Included among the volumes are diaries from his youth.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The William Cannicott Olson Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1976, 1978, 1982, 1985, and 1988.
Biographical Note
Chronology List
1965 B.A., Political Science, Duke University
1965-1968 Taught Social Studies at a high school
1968 M.A., University of North Carolina
1974 Ph.D., Latin American Studies, University of North Carolina
1970 Professor, Marist College
1975 Chairman of the History and Political Science Dept., Marist College
Contents of Collection
Collection contains mainly papers pertaining to his work in the field of education. Prior to his position at Marist College, he taught history in Danville, Va. He was active in the Danville Education Assoc., and became the Virginia Education Association's president. In addition to professional correspondence, there is a great deal of personal correspondence with family and friends much of which relates to his life as a homosexual. Included also are financial papers, printed materials, clippings, addresses, writings (including a draft of his dissertation), and other records. There is some memorabilia from Olson's school days. Included among the volumes are diaries from his youth.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Olson, William Cannicott
Danville Education Association
Virginia Education Association
Duke University
Marist College
Theta Chi
Danville (Va.)--Education
History teachers -- Virginia
Gays -- Correspondence
Diaries
Contents of Collection
- William Cannicott Olson Papers, 1956-1985, (13 boxes)
  - Academic records, 1962-1970 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1974-1977
  - Correspondence, 1961-1971
  - Writings
  - Correspondence, March 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1974-15 April 1975 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 16 April 1975-July 1976 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, August 1976-July 1977 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, August 1977-December 1977 (Box 7)
  - Danville Education Association
    - Clippings and papers
    - Salary committee (Box 8)
  - Financial papers, 1959-1977
  - Genealogy
  - Legal papers, 1965-1972
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1973-1977 and undated (Box 9)
  - NEA: Clippings and printed materials
  - Pictures
  - Theta Chi fraternity, 1962-1970 (Box 10)
  - Model UN materials
  - Virginia Education Association (Box 11)
    - Conventions, 1968-1969
    - Local conferences, 1968
    - Printed materials, 1966-1968
  - Writings, including dissertations (Box 12)
  - Volumes (Box 13)
- Unprocessed Additions, 1986-1998, (5 boxes)
  Includes unsorted, unarranged materials such as correspondence, finances, and writings from an accession in 1986 as well as Acc. 1998-0214.
  - 1986 and 1998 additions (Box 1-5)